# Maxim Kashchenko

Chiang Mai, Thailand +66 83-079-2969 mkaschenko@me.com https://mkaschenko.github.io https://github.com/mkaschenko

I develop software for more than 10 years, mostly web applications. I'm experienced with Ruby, Clojure and SQL. Also gained knowledge about TypeScript.

I solved problems in various domains, led teams, mentored colleagues, was part of product and outsourcing teams, worked remotely and onsite.

I can help you to collect requirements, transfer knowledge to people, lay the foundation for the new app, design and implement key functionality, refactor the hairy one and more.

I'm familiar with agile methodologies, continues delivery (CD), test (TDD), behaviour (BDD) and data driven development. Like to work with small teams up to 6 engineers and pair programming.

## **Technical Skills**

# **Likes:** ruby clojure sql **Dislikes:** angular

# Experience

## Software engineer / Team lead - Lockstep Labs

Feb 2016 → Feb 2019

Domains: e-commerce, visual analytics for retail banks, personal insurance in USA, education.

Languages: Ruby, Clojure, SQL, JavaScript, TypeScript.

Participated in development of different products, designed and implemented key functionality, led teams, on-boarded new team members, collected feedback from colleagues.

# $\textbf{Software engineer} - \underline{\mathsf{HipFlat}}$

Aug 2014 → Oct 2015

Domains: real estate, crawling and parsing.

Languages: Ruby, JavaScript.

Participated in development of the product, designed and implemented key functionality, attended to architecture and performance of the backend system.

# Ruby on Rails Developer / Team Lead – Arhont Information Security

Mar 2012 → Aug 2014

Domains: virtual data rooms, parsing

Languages: Ruby, SQL.

Participated in development of the product, designed and implemented key functionality, attended to architecture and performance of the backend system, led the team, introduced and applied agile methodologies.

# Ruby on Rails Developer - Tulp.ru

Mar 2010 → Oct 2011

Domains: review sites.

Languages: Ruby, SQL, JavaScript.

Participated in development of the product, worked on both backend and frontend systems.

# Ruby on Rails Developer – JazzCloud

Sep 2009 → Mar 2010

Domains: e-commerce, scheduling systems.

Languages: Ruby, JavaScript.

Participated in development of different products, worked on both backend and frontend systems.

## Ruby on Rails Developer - Development mill

Jun 2007 → Aug 2009

Domains: crawling and parsing, content management systems (CMS).

Languages: Ruby, Javascript.

Participated in development of different products, worked on both backend and frontend systems.

#### **Education**

M.Sc. in Databases (half-done) – Omsk State Technical University (OSTU)

Mathematics, software design and development, databases, networks.

B.Sc. in Informatics and Computer Science – Omsk State Technical University (OSTU)

 $2006 \rightarrow 2010$ 

Mathematics, informatics, software design and development, databases.

# Readings

**Test Driven Development** – Kent Beck – http://www.amazon.co.uk/Driven-Development-Addison-Wesley-Signature-Series/dp/0321146530

On the criteria to be used in decomposing systems into modules – D. L Parnas – http://www.amazon.co.uk/criteria-used-decomposing-systems-modules/dp/B0007BQZVU

 $\label{lem:condition} \textbf{Refactoring: Improving the Design of Existing Code} - \text{Martin Fowler, Kent Beck, John Brant, William Opdyke, Don Roberts - http://www.amazon.co.uk/Refactoring-Improving-Existing-Addison-Wesley-Technology-ebook/dp/B007WTFWJ6} - \text{Martin Fowler, Kent Beck, John Brant, William Opdyke, Don Roberts - http://www.amazon.co.uk/Refactoring-Improving-Existing-Addison-Wesley-Technology-ebook/dp/B007WTFWJ6} - \text{Martin Fowler, Kent Beck, John Brant, William Opdyke, Don Roberts - http://www.amazon.co.uk/Refactoring-Improving-Existing-Addison-Wesley-Technology-ebook/dp/B007WTFWJ6} - \text{Martin Fowler, Kent Beck, John Brant, William Opdyke, Don Roberts - http://www.amazon.co.uk/Refactoring-Improving-Existing-Addison-Wesley-Technology-ebook/dp/B007WTFWJ6} - \text{Martin Fowler, Martin F$ 

**Quantum Psychology: How Brain Software Programs You and Your World** – Robert Anton Wilson – http://www.amazon.co.uk/Quantum-Psychology-Brain-Software-Programs/dp/1561840718

Structure and Interpretation of Computer Programs – Harold Abelson, Gerald Jay Sussman, Julie Sussman – https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/43713.Structure\_and\_Interpretation\_of\_Computer\_Programs

**Tools** 

Favorite Editor: Emacs

 $2010 \rightarrow 2011$